<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A DIY approach to simulation, the universe and everything else</title>
    <link>https://danielssim.github.io/site/</link>
    <description>Recent content on A DIY approach to simulation, the universe and everything else</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://danielssim.github.io/site/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Decarbonize</title>
      <link>https://danielssim.github.io/site/notes_reviews/decarbonization_strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielssim.github.io/site/notes_reviews/decarbonization_strategy/</guid>
      <description>Work in progress. People wanted to read a draft state, so here you go.
I spent two months looking into the general strategy of country-wide decarbonization. My example here is Germany but all calculations are on a per-person level. Converting this to any other country should only be a small effort.
My target is to build a baseline mental model of energy supply and CO2 reduction on a country-wide level. Be warned that &amp;ldquo;baseline model&amp;rdquo; is way less than a detailed expert model: the model serves as a robust rough guide to the state of the world, but there are a lot of small details missing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you&#39;re (in) a large organization, why are you so inefficient?</title>
      <link>https://danielssim.github.io/site/notes_reviews/org_efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielssim.github.io/site/notes_reviews/org_efficiency/</guid>
      <description>(Crosspost: Reddit, includes comments + discussion. Reading length: maybe 5..10 minutes. Sorry for the messy structure: my thinking is not organized, so my writeup shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be either.)
I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about this a lot lately. After discussing this with several people I trust, I find the answers I have come up with still lacking and I&amp;rsquo;d appreciate feedback and pointers to things I&amp;rsquo;m missing.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been struck recently with how bad large organizations are at getting stuff done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What markets can and cannot do</title>
      <link>https://danielssim.github.io/site/notes_reviews/market_mechanisms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielssim.github.io/site/notes_reviews/market_mechanisms/</guid>
      <description>I spent some time reading up on economics and figured I might as well just write a summary. Quick warnings:
 Reading time: 30 minutes for the post, 5h+ if you follow all links. I highly recommend following the links. At least pick a few interesting ones. I mostly buy into a pro-market view here. If you are very much against capitalism per se, this post will probably not be worth your time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: An Essay on Man (Ernst Cassirer, 1944)</title>
      <link>https://danielssim.github.io/site/notes_reviews/review_cassirer_essay_on_man/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielssim.github.io/site/notes_reviews/review_cassirer_essay_on_man/</guid>
      <description>attention conservation notice: ~5400 words split over parts prologue, part 1, part 1.5, part 2 and summary
This is a review I wrote for the SlateStarCodex / AstralCodexTen book review contest. For whatever reason, it never arrived in the pile of contestants, so I’m posting it here instead. This is OK for me: I mostly wrote this for myself and really did enjoy the process. Nonetheless, I’d like others to read it and get some feedback on it (if you want to, use the comment function here).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
